Until this point, everything we've done has been
目前为止 我们所做的只是
related to loading and preparing the data.
数据加载和预处理
In this cell, we start actually building our deep neutral network.
在这个代码格中 我们开始正式搭建深度神经网络
First, we load TensorFlow.
首先 我们导入 TensorFlow 库
Later we will use this EPOCHS variable,
后面 我们会使用这个 EPOCHS (轮数) 变量
to tell TensorFlow how many times to run our training data through the network.
来告诉 TensorFlow 需要在神经网络中运行多少次训练数据
In general, the more EPOCHS,
一般而言轮数越多
the better our model will train,
模型的训练效果就越好
but also the longer training will take.
但训练花费的时间也会越长
Later we'll also use the batch size variable,
后面 我们还会使用批量大小 (batch size) 这一变量
to tell TensorFlow, how many training images to run through the network at a time.
来告诉 TensorFlow 每次在神经网络中运行的训练图像有多少个
The larger the batch size,
批量越大
the faster our model will train,
模型的训练速度就越快
but our processor may have a memory limit on how large a batch it can run.
但每次运行的批量受到内存大小的限制
Now we come to LeNet,
接下来 我们看一下 LeNet 网络
which is the core of the lab.
这是本次实验的核心
First we set more hyper parameters.
首先 我们要设置更多的超参数
In this case both hyper parameters relate to how we initialize our weights.
在本例中 两个超参数都和如何初始化权重相关
You can experiment with these values and see if you can do better than what we have here.
你可以尝试改变这些超参数 看看能否获得更好的结果
Then, we build the first convolutional layer.
然后 我们构建第一个卷积层
This layer has a five by five filter,
该层有一个 5×5 大小的滤波器
with an input depth of one,
输入深度为 1
and an output depth of six.
输出深度为 6
We also initialize the bias,
我们还需要对偏差进行初始化
then we use the conv2D function to convolve the filter over the images,
然后 我们使用 conv2D 函数对图像和滤波器进行卷积运算
and we add the bias at the end.
最后再加上偏差
The formula for convolutions tells us that the output height equals,
卷积公式告诉我们 输出高度等于
the input height minus the filter height,
输入高度减去滤波器高度 再加上 1
plus one all divided by the vertical stride.
最后整体除以垂直方向的步长
In this case, that means 32, minus 5,
在这个例子中 具体值是 32 减去 5 加上 1
plus 2, all divided by 1, which equals 28.
最后整体除以 1 等于 28
The formula works the same way for the output width,
这个公式同样适用于计算输出的宽度
which also equals 28.
也等于 28
So our convolutional layer output is 28 by 28 by 6.That's our first convolutional layer.
因此 卷积层的输出大小就是 28×28×6 这是我们的第一个卷积层
Next, we activate the output of the convolutional layer,
接下来 我们需要激活卷积层的输出
in this case with a ReLU activation function.
在本例中 我们使用 ReLU 激活函数
Then we pool the output,
然后我们使用一个大小为 2×2 卷积核 并以 2×2 的步长
using the 2 by 2 kernel with a 2 by 2 stride,
对输出进行池化
which gives us a pooling output of 14 by 14 by 6.
这样我们获得一个大小为 14×14×6 的池化输出
The network then runs through another set of convolutional activation and pooling layers,
然后 数据进入另一套卷积、激活和池化层中
giving an output of 5 by 5 by 16.
并得到了一个大小为 5×5×16 的输出
Then we flatten this output into a vector.
然后 我们把该输出排成一列 得到一个向量
The length of the vector is 5 times 5 times 16, which equals 400.
该向量的长度为 5×5×16 也就是 400
We pass this vector into a fully connected layer,
我们把该向量导入一个全连接层
with a width of 120.
层的宽度为 120
Then we apply a ReLU activation to the output of this fully connected layer.
并对这个全连接层的输出使用 ReLU 激活函数
We repeat that pattern again this time with a layer width of 84.
重复上述过程 这次全连接层的宽度是 84
Finally, we attach a fully connected output layer,
最后 我们加入一个全连接输出层
with a width, equal to the number of classes in our label set.
层的宽度等于标签集所包含的类别数
In this case,we have 10 classes,
在这个例子中 共有 10 个类别
One for each digit,
每一位对应一个类别
so the with the the output layer is 10.
所以输出层的宽度为 10
These outputs are also known as our logits,
这些输出也被称为对数几率 (logits)
which is what we return from the LeNet function.
也就是从 LeNet 返回的结果
So that is the entire LeNet architecture.
这就是 LeNet 的整体架构
Now we just have to put it to use.
接下去 我们来学习它的具体应用